Prasad J

Full Stack Developer

(+91) 97890 45593

raghav21prasad@gmail.com

Ohennai, India

JPrasad21

in JPrasad21

Full Stack Developer with 4+ years of experience in the field of web development using JavaScript frameworks (Angular 12+, ReactJs, NextJs, NestJs) and C#. A developer who likes to work in a challenging environment to bring out the best solutions.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Angular 12+
- ReactJs and NextJs
- HTML5, CSS3, JQuery
- C#
- NestJs
- PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

Rajalakshmi Engineering College

Bachelor's of Engineering in ECE

CGPA: 7.8/10

June 2014 - May 2018

Sri Ahobila Math Oriental Higher Secondary School

12th standard

PERCENTAGE: 95.58%

May 2014

LANGUAGES

- English
- Tamil
- Kannada

WORK EXPERIENCE

Botminds Inc

January 2020 - Present

Al Engineer

- Worked in Table AI feature to Identify and extract essential information from table using Angular and JQuery
- Implemented Okta integration for Single Sign On (SSO) with OIDC method using C# and Angular
- Built Auto derivation library a post prediction process where customised logics applied to derive new values
- Developed a dashboard widget where the columns, filters can be customised for analytics using C# and Angular
- Implemented document stage management to keep track of the document's current stage and user using c# and Angular
- Improved product stability and performance to seamlessly load and render documents to provide better user experience
- Worked in developing the SEO friendly enterprise website using NextJs to get maximum reach in marketing campaign

Tata Consultancy Services Assistant System Engineer

June 2018 - December 2019

- Worked as an R&I Developer in CTO Incubation team to build web applications for Drones and ChatBot creator platform
- Developed UI platform to create, train and interact with AI-powered Chatbots using Angular 7
- Developed backend API's to create hierarchical model for drones to identify objects in a warehouse using Python flask framework

PROJECTS

Web Based Resume

September 2022

 Created this resume using ReactJs and downloaded resume as PDF using puppeteer. This can be viewed at https://prasad-resume-2022.surge.sh/

Vizhithiru App

December 2020 - February 2021

 Created an application for logging and escalating complaints in ReactJs to notify the election department about the common issues